Preliminary Inventory to the Robert Tryon Frederick Papers, 1928-1967
Hoover Institution Archives
Robert Tryon Frederick papers,
1928-1967
68009
Frederick, Robert Tryon, 1907-1970
8 manuscript boxes, 1 album box, 3 envelopes, 3 motion picture film reels (3.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, diaries, writings, memoranda, photographs, and motion picture film, relating to operations of the First Special Service Force in Italy and France during World War II, and to the American Military Mission to Greece in 1951.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
First Special Service Force.; United States. Army--Officers.; United States. Military Mission to Greece.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--France.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Italy.; Canada.; Greece.; United States--Armed Forces.; Moving-pictures.
Biography
Major general, United States Army; commanding general, First Special Service Force, 1942-1944; head, Military Mission to Greece, 1951.
Container List
- First Special Service Force (F.S.S.F.) History, 1942 July 9-1944 June 30 (Box 1.)
- Telephone conversation transcript between Colonel Frederick and others concerning F.S.S.F., 1942-1943 (Box 1.)
- F.S.S.F. Memoranda, manuscripts, maps, etc., 1942 (Box 1.)
- Plough project with map of important Norway hydro-electric stations, memoranda, minutes of meetings, etc. (Box 1.)
- Plough project diary, 1942 (Box 1.)
- F.S.S.F. Miscellany (Box 1.)
- F.S.S.F. Correspondence, memoranda, orders, etc., 1942-1943 (Box 2.)
- F.S.S.F. Field orders, memoranda, correspondence, maps, 1943-1944 (Box 3.)
- F.S.S.F. - History, other matters. Correspondence, 1942-1960 (Box 3.)
- Maps - Rome, Nürnberg, Munich, campaigns in Central Europe, etc. (Box 3.)
- F.S.S.F. Correspondence, memoranda, etc. of Plough project, 1942-1943
- 179th Infantry Regiment: The Story of a Regiment, 1946 (Box 3.)
- First Airborne Task Force, General Frederick, France, Italy, etc., 1944. Correspondence, memoranda, etc. (Box 4.)
- Orders, etc., 1942-1948 (Box 4.)
- Orders, correspondence, etc., 1928-1952 (Box 4.)
- Correspondence, speech, etc., 1928-1948 (Box 4.)
- Memorabilia (Box 4.)
- Correspondence, 1944-1960 (Box 4.)
- 45th Infantry Division, 1945-1966 (Box 4.)
- Photographs, citations, history, miscellany of General Frederick (Box 4.)
- Plough project, 1942 (Box 4.)
- General Frederick's assignment with the American Military Mission to Greece, 1951. Correspondence, manuscripts, printed matter (Box 5.)
- Correspondence with Prince of Monaco, 1944, and other VIPs, 1942-1959 (Box 5.)
- Road to Rome (Box 5.)
- Speeches by General Frederick, ca. 1942-1950. Includes photostats of maps (Box 5.)
- Amphibious training materials (Box 5.)
- Field Orders (Box 5.)
- "The Devil's Brigade." Film script, 1967 (Box 6.)
- Telephone directory, Headquarters U.S. Forces, Vienna, Austria, 1948 October (Box 6.)
- Memorabilia (Box 6.)
- Anzio Beachhead, Historical Division, Department of the Army, 1947 (Box 6.)
- From the Volturno to the Winter Line, Military Intelligence Division, U.S. War Department [1944] (Box 6.)
- The Winter Line, Military Intelligence Division, U.S. War Department [1945] (Box 6.)
- The 45th Division Artillery (Box 6.)
- The Invasion of Southern France, General Jacob L. Devers (Box 6.)
- For You, For Me, For Us, Fannie S. Wilson (Box 6.)
- German court martial order, 1945 April 1 (Box 6.)
- "From Salerno to Cassino," Manuscript by Martin Blumenson (Box 7.)
- "The Devil's Brigade," Photocopy of manuscript by Robert H. Adleman (Box 8.)
- "The First Special Service Force: A War History of the North Americans, 1942-1944," Manuscript by Robert D. Burhans, with comments by Robert T. Frederick (Box 8.)
- Declassified records, 1942-1950
  - August 2011 release of records, 1942-1950 (Box 8)
    - F.S.S.F. correspondence, orders, 1942-1950 (Box 8)
    - Plough project, 1942 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, orders, etc., 1942-1950 (Box 8)
    - Role of Army in Future War photographs, 1948 (Box 8)